(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
遥か天空（そら）響いている
Echoing in the distant skies,
祈りは奇跡に
prayers become miracles.
真夜中の蒼に溶けて
Dissolving into the blue midnight,
流れてく涙の粒
my flowing teardrops...
迷いなく包み込む
Without hesitation,
温もりに出逢った
I met a warmth that enveloped me.
真っ白な雪のように
Like pure white snow,
どこまでも素直なコトバ
your words are honest through and through.
鉄の羽根纏った
Even clad in wings of iron,
僕を動かしてく
they move me forward.
傷つくたびに
Every time I'm hurt,
優しくなれる
I can become kinder.
君のその笑顔だけ
I only want to protect
守り抜きたい
your smile alone;
願いはひとつ
that is my one wish.
時を越え刻まれた
Memories of sorrow
悲しみの記憶
carved across time...
真っ直ぐに受け止める
I'll accept them head-on;
君は光の天使
you are an angel of light.
あの日胸に灯った
The eternal flame
永遠の炎
lit in my heart that day...
深い闇解き放って
Releases the deep darkness
自由の扉開いてく
and opens the door to freedom.
強く果てない未来へ
Toward a strong and endless future.
冷たい緑の月に 映し出す心の影
The cold green moon projects the shadow of my heart.
寂しげに呟いた 「君のそばにいたい」
I lonely whispered, "I want to be by your side."
真実と向き合うこと 教えてくれた勇気は
The courage you gave me to face the truth...
僕を駆け巡って 夢に目覚めてゆく
races through me as I awaken from my dream.
触れ合う気持ち
So our feelings of contact
離れないように
never part,
しっかりと抱きしめて
hold me tightly.
確かな想い貫いてゆく
I'll carry through these certain emotions.
銀の海に隠した
A blank page hidden
空白のページ
in the silver sea...
君だけが知っている
Show me the "truth"
「本当」を僕に見せて
that only you know.
吹き荒れる切なさに
A vow born
生まれゆく誓い
from the raging pain.
もう何も怖くはないよ
I'm no longer afraid of anything;
結んだ視線そらさずに
without turning my gaze away...
大切な「今」始める
I'll start this precious "now."
君が君でいられる場所
The place where you can be yourself,
幻にさらわれぬように
so you won't be swept away by illusions.
消えない雨の苦しみも
Even the pain of the never-ending rain...
鍵を壊してぶつけてよ
break the lock and let it out.
隣にいるから 全てを信じて
Because I'm by your side, believe in everything.
時を越え刻まれた
Memories of sorrow
悲しみの記憶
carved across time...
真っ直ぐに受け止める
I'll accept them head-on;
君は光の天使
you are an angel of light.
あの日胸に灯った
The eternal flame
永遠の炎
lit in my heart that day...
深い闇解き放って
Releases the deep darkness...
解き放って
Set it free
自由の扉 開いてく
Opening the door of freedom
強く果てない未来へ
To a strong, endless future
そう いつどこから 始まる
Yes, starting from whenever, wherever
お待たせみんなー！
Sorry for the wait, everyone!
今年もポルカの誕生日が始まったー！
Polka's birthday has begun again this year!
タイトルは、あ、かっこいい、
The title is, ah, so cool,
「Glitter of Love」！
It's "Glitter of Love"!
というわけで、ハッシュタグはこちら！
So, here's the hashtag!
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026 でいっぱい、いっぱい呟いてねー！
Tweet a lot with #OmaruPolkaBirthday2026!
はい！いやー、今回のテーマがまず、
Yes! Well, the theme this time is first of all,
愛と勇気と戦う女の子になってます。
about girls fighting with love and courage.
そして見てくださいこのステージ！えいっ！はっ！すごい広い！
And look at this stage! Ei! Ha! It's so wide!
なんとですね、広いんですけど、
It's wide, but more importantly,
まずスクリーンが超デカい！大迫力！
first of all, the screen is huge! So powerful!
なんとなくいつもの3倍くらい頑張ってもらいました！
We somehow made it work with about three times the effort!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
というわけでですね、ここからゲストの方々が
And so, from here on, many guests...
たくさんいらっしゃいます！
...will be appearing!
もうホロメンだけでたぶん尾丸ポルカ史上最多のゲスト数だと思っております！
I think this is the most guests in Polka's history, just with Hololive members!
それをね、これからノンストップでお送りするので、
I'll be bringing that to you non-stop from now on,
楽しんでいってください！
so please enjoy!
というわけで、いくぞー！
With that said, let's go!
星天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross
光と飛沫のキス
A kiss of light and spray
虹のように咲かせよう
Let it bloom like a rainbow
恋のような
Like a romance...
虹の Birthday
...a rainbow Birthday
どんな美しい日も
Even on the most beautiful days
何かが生まれる 何かが死ぬ
Something is born, something dies
せめて歌を I love you
At least through song, I love you
世界がひどい地獄だとしても
Even if the world is a terrible hell
せめて伝えよう I love you
At least let me tell you, I love you
解放の時は来た
The time for liberation has come
星降る天へと響き飛べ
Resonate and fly to the star-filled sky
Everybody shout!
Stardust!
そして奇跡は待つものじゃなくて
And miracles aren't things you wait for
その手で作るものと吼えろ
Shout that they're things you make with your own hands
涙した過去も苦味も レクイエムにして
Make the tearful past and bitterness into a requiem
聖なる全力で
With all your sacred might
輝けフューチャー！
Shine, future!
信じ照らせ 星天ギャラクシィクロス
Believe and illuminate, Seiten Galaxy Cross
一人じゃないことを
That you are not alone
やがて君は知る日のため
For the day you will eventually know
指先伝う熱を
The heat traveling through your fingertips
分かち合って 明日に向かう
Share it and face tomorrow
永久なる空に I feel you
In the eternal sky, I feel you
自由の魂は 穢せはしない
The soul of freedom cannot be defiled
不滅なる夢に I feel you
In the immortal dream, I feel you
代償の剣を握れ
Grasp the sword of compensation
運命も終局も断ち切る力で
With the power to cut through fate and the finale
そして奏でた勇気
And the courage we played
不滅の煌めき
An undying sparkle,
十字となって闇を暴く
becoming a cross to expose the darkness.
駆け抜けたその先には
Beyond where we ran through,
神様も知らない
even God doesn't know.
歴史が光誇る My Super Brave
History takes pride in the light, my super brave.
この絆
This bond,
星天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross!
逆光の翼で
With wings of backlighting,
YES, JUST BELIEVE
燃え盛る炎追って
chasing the blazing flames,
BIG MISSION
過去背負い戦おう
let's fight, carrying our pasts.
そして奇跡は待つものじゃなくて
And miracles aren't something to wait for...
その手で作るものと吠えろ
howl that they are something you make with your hands!
何度だって何度だって
Over and over again,
立ち上がろうか
shall we stand up?
正義ある善の力で
With the power of righteous goodness,
輝け Future world
shine, Future world.
信じ照らせ
Believe and illuminate,
星天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross!
Let's sing! Let's swing! Let's dance! Let's born! Let's smile! Let's fly! Woo! Precure!
ときめき見上げ 変わってく世界 未来
Heart throbbing, looking up, the world and future change.
1+1+1は無限
1+1+1 equals infinity.
唇からこぼれる歌は…
The song overflowing from our lips is...
プリズム 眩しい光
A prism's dazzling light.
三人寄れば文殊 最高
Three heads are the best!
始まるただ一度の ライブ Enjoy together
The start of a one-time live, enjoy together.
Awakening Harmony
暗闇の真ん中
In the middle of the darkness
まっすぐな眼差し
With a straight gaze
立ち上がる姿
The sight of you rising up
ちゃんと見ていたよ
I was watching you closely
閉じ込められそうな
Seemingly about to be trapped
心を奮い立たせ
Rousing your heart
収まり切らない
Uncontainable
輝きを放ち
Emitting a radiance
射抜かれた胸の奥
Deep in my pierced chest
泣きついたままじゃ不相応
It's unbecoming to stay crying
それだけでもう
That alone is already
理由になる
A reason enough
待っていて
Wait for me...
取り戻したい
I want to take back
光の世界
The world of light
その笑顔
That smile
勇気
Courage
涙
Tears
夢希望の証
Proof of dreams and hope
響け明日を
Resonate towards tomorrow
願う力から
From the power of wishing
生まれる
Is born
私たちのハーモニー
Our harmony
響け
Resonate!
それでも暗闇は
Even so, the darkness
訪れてしまうもの
Is something that will visit
惑わされないで
Don't be led astray
君は君だから
Because you are who you are
分かち合えた日々が
The days we shared together
ハートを輝かせる
Make our hearts shine
一人じゃないこと
That you're not alone
気付かせてくれる
It makes me realize
抱え切れないほどの
More than I can carry
ありがとうの代わりに
Instead of just saying "thank you"
鍵をかけて
Locking it in
一つになる受け止めて
Becoming one, please accept it
取り戻すんだ
I'm going to take it back
光の未来
The future of light
今熱い思い繋げ
Connecting these burning feelings now
叶えに行くよ
I'm going to make it come true
君と一緒に
Together with you
願える奇跡
The miracle we can wish for
重ねて
Layering them
広がっていくハーモニー
The harmony that keeps spreading
響け
Resonate!
目覚める時が来たね
The time to awaken has come
本当の自分になる
To become my true self
満ちる運命
A fulfilling fate
取り戻したい
I want to take back
光の世界
The world of light
その笑顔
That smile
勇気
Courage
涙
Tears
夢希望の証
Proof of dreams and hope
君と明日を
With you, towards tomorrow
願う力から
From the power of wishing
生まれる
Is born
私たちのハーモニー
Our harmony
響け
Resonate!
トライアングル・ドリーマー
Triangle Dreamer
Day by Day 日に日に
Day by day, more and more
募るの乙女心
A young girl's feelings grow
同じ
The same...
おんなじクラス斜め前のおとなしい人
The quiet person sitting diagonally in front in the same class
カッコ良くはない だけど優しい
He's not cool, but he's kind
いつも頼れる彼
He's always someone I can rely on
after school 恋愛相談の帰り道
After school, on the way home from talking about love
なんだって話せる親友の女の子
My best friend, a girl I can talk to about anything
スポーツ万能
She's good at sports
勉強もできて
Good at studying too
女子力MAXです
Her femininity is at its max
どこにでもある
It happens anywhere
よくあること
It's something common
急に彼女が
Suddenly, she says...
「あのね、実は私好きな人がいるのって」
“Hey, actually, I have someone I like”
ちょ、マジで！
Wait, seriously?!
トライアングル！ トライアングル！
Triangle! Triangle!
この恋は支離滅裂
This love is chaotic
一瞬で 一瞬で
In an instant, in an instant
崩れ去る
It crumbles
バランス
The balance
ベタな漫画みたいなフラグ
A cliché manga-like flag
まさか自分も立てちゃうなんて残念すぎます
It's too bad I'm the one who triggered it
トライアングル！ トライアングル！
Triangle! Triangle!
この恋は不安定
This love is unstable
なんちゃって
Just kidding
なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
A category that “just kidding” can't fix
恋と友情
Love and friendship
ゆらゆら揺れてなんか
Swaying back and forth
青春しちゃってます
I'm living my youth
私困っちゃいます
I'm in trouble
乾杯で お似合いすぎるわ
A toast, you two look too good together
さて、困難
Now, a difficulty...
悔しいけど
It's frustrating, but...
どーか そんなんじゃなくて 本心
Somehow... that's not it, my true feelings
っていうか すでに
Or rather, already...
応援モード
In cheer mode
むしろ すがすがしい
Actually, it's refreshing
だけど彼女は
But she has...
不思議な顔
A strange look on her face
真剣なんだって
She's serious
そうじゃなくて 私あなたが 好き ごめんって
No, that's not it... “I like you, sorry”
ちょ、マジで！
Wait, seriously?!
トライアングル！ トライアングル！
Triangle! Triangle!
この恋は支離滅裂
This love is chaotic
一瞬で 一瞬で
In an instant, in an instant
崩れ去るバランス
The balance crumbles
私 あなた
Me, you,
彼女と私
her and me
超絶複雑百合展開は想定外です
This super complex yuri development is unexpected
トライアングル！ トライアングル！
Triangle! Triangle!
この恋は不安定
This love is unstable
なんちゃって
Just kidding
なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
A category that “just kidding” can't fix
解けないパズル 与えたもうた
You gave me an unsolvable puzzle
神様 恨んじゃいます
God, I'll resent you
私 悩んじゃいます
I'm worrying
ああもう！
Ah, geez!
すごいやばい！
This is really bad!
きたよ！
It's here!
きたけど、
It came, but...
えっ、そういう意味じゃなくて！
Wait, not in that sense!
だって女の子同士だし！
I mean, we're both girls!
ねぇ神様、どうしたらいいの？
Hey God, what should I do?
私、どうしたいの？
What do I want to do?
ヘルプ・ミー！
Help me!
なんか変だ 愛に国境も年も性別も関係ない
It's strange. Love has no borders, age, or gender
けど
But...
トライアングル！ トライアングル！
Triangle! Triangle!
この恋は支離滅裂
This love is chaotic
一瞬で 一瞬で
In an instant, in an instant
崩れ去るバランス
The balance crumbles
普通の恋 夢見てたのに
I was dreaming of a normal love
ノーマル捨てての私じゃちょっと無理ゲーすぎます
Discarding normalcy is a bit too much of a “muda game” for me
トライアングル！ トライアングル！
Triangle! Triangle!
この恋は不安定
This love is unstable
なんちゃって
Just kidding
なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
A category that “just kidding” can't fix
彼女のこと 好きになれたら
If only I could fall in love with her...
なんて 妄想しちゃいます
Just kidding, I'm fantasizing
私 どかしてます
I'm going crazy
PHOENIX PRAYER / 作詞・作曲：中村未来
PHOENIX PRAYER / Lyrics & Composition: Miku Nakamura
劫々とつづくショートショート
A short story that goes on and on
喪失は絶対零度だ
Loss is absolute zero
今夜はリィンカーネーション
Tonight is a reincarnation
哀しみが混沌の子守唄うたってるよ
Sorrow is singing a lullaby of chaos
運命に理由があるのならば
If there's a reason for fate...
すべてを賭けてみたいの
...I want to risk it all
あなたを守りたい
I want to protect you
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
I can fly as high as I want
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can become stronger and stronger as I want
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of us meeting
切り開くわ 不死鳥の炎 抱いて
I'll carve a path, embracing the phoenix's flame
あなたの側 高く高く
By your side, higher and higher...
眼差し 抱きたくなるの
...I start wanting to hold your gaze
Flashback, flashback 振りほどけ
Flashback, flashback, shake it off
汗 挑み続けろ
Sweat, keep on challenging
飄々と佇む ほとほと
Standing aloof, quite weary...
私が必要でしょう
...you need me, don't you?
今夜はリィンカーネーション
Tonight is a reincarnation
正しさがストレス最前線に 押し出すよ
Correctness pushes us to the front lines of stress
運命に理由があるのならば
If there's a reason for fate...
優しい世界をあげたい
...I want to give you a gentle world
あなたを包むわ
I'll embrace you
どこまでも早く射抜くわ
I'll pierce through as fast as I want
どこまでも熱く熱く焦がすわ
I'll burn hotter and hotter as I want
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of us meeting
切り開くわ 不死鳥の炎 抱いて
I'll carve a path, embracing the phoenix's flame
あなたの側 高く高く
By your side, higher and higher...
鏡越し 光を見せて
...show me the light through the mirror
Flashback, flashback 許さない
Flashback, flashback, no forgiveness
偽証 進み続けろ
Perjury, keep on moving forward
尽きるまで
Until I'm exhausted
側に居ると
When I'm by your side...
鼓動が早くて 目眩がする
...my heart beats faster and my head spins
すべて捧げる もう決めたの
I've already decided to give my everything
最後のチャンスだから もう離さない
Because it's the last chance, I won't let go
あなたに貰う 未来の風
The wind of the future I receive from you...
重なっていけ
...let it overlap
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
I can fly as high as I want
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can become stronger and stronger as I want
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of us meeting
闇夜をも 望めば 輝夜にするから
Because if you wish, I'll turn even the dark night into a moonlit one
切り開くわ 不死鳥の炎 抱いて
I'll carve a path, embracing the phoenix's flame
あなたの側 高く高く
By your side, higher and higher...
眼差し 抱きたくなるの
...I start wanting to hold your gaze
Flashback, flashback 振りほどけ
Flashback, flashback, shake it off
汗 挑み続けろ
Sweat, keep on challenging
あなたの側 高く高く
By your side, higher and higher...
鏡越し 光を見せて
...show me the light through the mirror
Flashback, flashback 許さない
Flashback, flashback, no forgiveness
偽証 進み続けろ
Perjury, keep on moving forward
尽きるまで
Until I'm exhausted
ダイアモンド クレバス
Diamond Crevasse
神様に恋をしてた頃は
Back when I was in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは
I never thought a parting like this
思ってなかったよ
would ever come.
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I can never touch you again,
せめて最後に
then at least for the last time,
もう一度抱きしめてほしかったよ
I wanted you to hold me one more time.
It's long, long goodbye
It's a long, long goodbye
さよなら、さよなら
Goodbye, goodbye.
何度だって
Over and over,
自分に無情に言い聞かせて
I tell myself heartlessly.
手を振るのは優しさだよねぇ
Waving goodbye is kindness, isn't it?
今強さが欲しい
Now I want strength.
あなたに出会い 輝いてた
Meeting you, I shone,
あたしが生まれて
I was born.
愛すればこそ
Because I loved,
愛あればこそ
Because there was love,
希望のない奇跡を待って
Waiting for a miracle without hope,
どうなるの
what's the point?
涙に滲む星의 瞬きは… go
The twinkling stars blurring in my tears... go
忘れないよ あなたの温もりも
I won't forget your warmth,
その優しさも
nor your kindness,
全て包んでくれた両手も
nor your hands that enveloped everything.
It's long, long goodbye
It's a long, long goodbye
さよなら、さよなら
Goodbye, goodbye.
愛おしい人
My beloved,
あなたがいたから歩いてこれた
I could walk this far because you were here.
一人なんかじゃなかったよねぇ
I wasn't alone after all, was I?
今答えが欲しい
Now I want the answer.
燃えるような流星掴まえて
Catching a burning meteor,
火を灯して
lighting a fire,
愛していたい 愛されてたい
I want to keep loving, I want to be loved.
冷えた身体一つで世界はどうなるの
What happens to the world with only this cold body?
貼り続けてた虚勢が溶けてく… long goodbye
The bravado I kept up melts away... long goodbye.
どうしてなの 涙あふれて
Why is it that my tears overflow
止められない
and I can't stop them?
あなたに出会い 輝いてた
Meeting you, I shone,
あたしが生まれて
I was born.
愛すればこそ
Because I loved,
愛あればこそ
Because there was love,
希望のない奇跡を待って
Waiting for a miracle without hope,
どうなるの
what's the point?
涙に滲む星の瞬きは…
The twinkling stars blurring in my tears...
もし生まれ変わってまた巡り会えるなら
If I'm reborn and we meet again,
その時もきっとあたしを見つけ出して
then please find me again without fail,
もう二度と離さないで捕まえてて
and catch me, never to let me go again.
ひとりじゃないと
That I'm not alone...
ささやいてほしい
I want you to whisper,
プラネット
Planet.
Paradise Lost
聖なる瞳が 痛みを映したら
If the holy eyes reflect the pain
振り向いてごらん
Turn around and look
情熱放つ Trick
A Trick that releases passion
崩れる足元 二人は戻れない
Our footing crumbles, the two can't return
差し伸べた手をほどかないで
Do not let go of the hand you reached out
消えるよ また 優しい日々が
They're vanishing again, those gentle days
思い出を汚すのは
Tainting our memories...
許せない
...is something I won't allow
ここは裏切りの木なの
This is a tree of betrayal
彷徨う心の果てに
At the end of a wandering heart
光を求めて
Seeking the light
祈る言葉届け 新たに
I'll send my prayers anew
囚われの羽が
The captive wings
遥かな空へと向かう
Head toward the distant sky
信じたいよ 私たち
I want to believe that we...
孤独じゃない
...are not alone
分かり合う
Understanding each other
絆の中
Within our bond
離さないで
Don't let go
始まる Destiny
The beginning destiny
新たな願いに
In a new wish
鎖解ける時
When the chains are undone
休ませてくれる
They let me rest
深い眠りに
In a deep sleep
わずかな希望が
A slight hope
私を強くする
Makes me stronger
温もりに触れてみたいから
Because I want to feel the warmth
蘇れば 儚き命
If resurrected, it's a fleeting life
繰り返す愛しさが導いた
A recurring love has guided us
胸に泡沫の調べ
An ephemeral melody in my chest
流れる世界の終わりに
At the end of a flowing world
諦めはしない
I will not give up
今が繋ぐ明日 探そう
Let's find the tomorrow that today connects to
千切れ舞う羽は
The torn and dancing wings
未来の空へと向かう
Head toward the sky of the future
忘れないで 私たち
Don't forget that we are
ひとつの Crystal
A single crystal
輝いて
Shine
割れないのよ
We won't break
離さないで
Don't let go
誓いの Destiny
Our destiny of oaths
離さない
I won't let go
見つめて Paradise Lost
Gaze upon Paradise Lost
Wow wow wow wow...
やっとみんな会えたね
It's time for us to meet at last
Don't stop! No, don't stop 'til finish!
ダダダッ 全力走りたい
D-D-D! I want to run at full power
芝と砂と君の追い切りメニュー
Turf and sand and your workout menu
タフな タフな
Tough, tough
声出せ 叫べ
Give it your voice, shout it out
それじゃ！ (ファイ！ オー！)
Here we go! (Fight! Oh!)
ダダダッ 全力上がりたい
D-D-D! I want to speed up at full power
譲れない 夢の途中
In the middle of a dream I won't give up
始めよう ここから最高速ストーリー
Let's begin, from here the fastest story
あぁ 憧れの地へ
Ah, toward the land of our dreams
語り合ったメモリーズ
The memories we shared
もっと ドキドキもっとトキメキ
More heart-pounding, more excitement
抑えられない たまんない
Unstoppable, I can't stand it
熱い ハラハラが止まらない
The hot suspense won't stop
輝け！
Shine!
キミと
With you
走り競い ゴール目指し
Running and competing, aiming for the goal
遥か響け 届けミュージック
Echo far and wide, reach out music
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと想い
Always, always, always, always thinking
夢がきっと叶うなら
If dreams are sure to come true
あの日キミに感じた
What I felt for you that day
何かを信じて
Believing in something
春も夏も秋も冬も越え 出逢い 憧れ走れ
Through spring, summer, fall and winter, meeting and running with longing
あぁ 勝利へ
Ah, toward victory
Don't stop! No, don't stop 'til finish!
ダダダッ 全力弾けたい
D-D-D! I want to burst out with full power
大出逢い 決意 絆になった
A great encounter and resolve became a bond
ハンジャン ハンジャン
Hands up, hands up
本気で叫べ
Shout it out with all your heart
それじゃ！ (ファイ！ オー！)
Here we go! (Fight! Oh!)
ダダダッ 全力笑いたい
D-D-D! I want to laugh at full power
風のど真ん中
Right in the eye of the storm
リアルに ここから上昇ストーリー
Realistically, from here an ascending story
あぁ 駆け抜けた日々
Ah, the days we ran through
語り合ったグローリー
The glory we talked about together
今応えたい 生きてると
I want to respond now, that I'm alive
背中押す声 熱く鳴り
The voices pushing my back ring out hot
夢は夢のまま 終われない
A dream cannot end as just a dream
響け！
Echo!
キミと
With you
未来描き ゴール目指し
Painting the future, aiming for the goal
狙い定め 掴めウィニング
Set your sights and grab the victory
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと想い
Always, always, always, always thinking
夢はきっと叶うから
Keep on dreaming, it's sure to come true
あの日キミが鳴らした
The sound you made that day
涙も信じて
Believing even in tears
雨も風も雲も闇も越え 出逢い 憧れ走れ
Through rain, wind, clouds and darkness, meeting and running with longing
あぁ 勝利へ
Ah, toward victory
揺るぎない 覚悟 決して
An unwavering determination, never...
一つ二つ 共に綴る記録
One by one, records we write together
背中に迫る迷い 振り払え
Shake off the hesitation closing in from behind
今の自分 追い越すだけ
Just overtake who you are now
勝ちたい
I want to win
キミと勝ちたい！
I want to win with you!
未来描き ゴール目指し
Painting the future, aiming for the goal
狙い定め 掴めウィニング
Set your sights and grab the victory
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと想い
Always, always, always, always thinking
夢はきっと叶うから
Keep on dreaming, it's sure to come true
あの日キミが鳴らした
The sound you made that day
涙も信じて
Believing even in tears
春も夏も秋も冬も越え
Through spring, summer, fall and winter
雨も風も越え 雲も闇も越え
Through rain and wind, through clouds and darkness
勝利へ
Toward victory
キミと
With you
走り競い ゴール目指し
Running and competing, aiming for the goal
遥か響け 届けミュージック
Echo far and wide, reach out music
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと想い
Always, always, always, always thinking
夢はきっと叶うなら
If dreams are sure to come true
あの日キミに感じた
What I felt for you that day
夏も 秋も 冬も 越え 願え 焦がれ 走れ
Crossing summer, autumn, and winter; wish, long, and run
あぁ 勝利へ
Ah, towards victory
It's finally the true end
I'm ready for... my destiny
I'm ready for... STARTING OVER
やっと幕を下ろせた 最後の瞬間まで
Finally, the curtain has fallen, until the very last moment
わたしは精一杯に わたしをやりきった
I did my best, I gave it my all
終演の続きは 誰も知らなくていい
No one needs to know what follows the end of the show
涙を置いて 新しい旅に出よう
Leave the tears behind and set out on a new journey
熱狂はあなたを選ぶ 違う結末だっただけ
The fervor chooses you, it was just a different ending
同じ愛になれなかった Destiny
A destiny where we couldn't become the same love
これまでの全てを 差し出すような愛だった
It was a love where I offered up everything until now
世界の意味が変わるくらいに 肯定された気がしたんだ
I felt affirmed, as if the meaning of the world had changed
何気なさの中で 気づけた最初の奇跡が
The first miracle I noticed in the midst of the ordinary...
あなたでよかった わたしでよかった 心から思えたよ
...was being glad it was you and glad it was me
ずっと遠い未来も ちゃんと覚えていよう
I'll make sure to remember even in the far-off future
自分の抱きしめ方 明日の願い方
How to hold myself, how to wish for tomorrow
あなたが いなくても わたしの片隅で
Even if you're not here, in a corner of my heart...
優しい光 消えたりしないとわかる
...I know the gentle light will never fade
今はまだ手を振れるほど 道は別れたばかりで
For now, I can still wave, as our paths have only just parted
後ろ髪に風を感じながら
While feeling the wind in my hair as I look back
それまでの全てが あなたに出会うためだった
Everything until then was for the sake of meeting you
どの瞬間もムダじゃないこと 本当の意味で知れたから
Because I've learned the true meaning of how no moment was wasted
次の曲がり角も 自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose the next corner in my own way
いつかに繋がる 新しい一歩 信じて歩き出そう
Believe and start walking a new step that leads to a 'sometime'
心から誰かを愛せた あの日々は
Those days when I could love someone from my heart...
間違いなくわたしの Destiny
...were undoubtedly my destiny
これまでの全てが 新しい力をくれる
Everything until now gives me new strength
どの瞬間もムダじゃないなら 何が起きても大丈夫だから
If no moment is wasted, then no matter what happens, it'll be okay
次の物語も 自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose the next story in my own way
いつかに繋がる わたしのはじまり 信じて歩き出そう
Believe and start walking towards my beginning that leads to a 'sometime'
いつかに繋がる わたしのはじまり
The beginning of me that connects to someday,
信じて歩き出そう
I'll believe and start walking.
再び幕は上がる
The curtain rises once again.
聴いていただいたのは新曲の「STARTING OVER」でした！
That was my new song, 'STARTING OVER'!
はい！新年一発目、新曲の初披露というわけで
Yes! It's the first new song of the year, a premiere!
ぬるっとね、新曲をやってしまったんですが
I just sort of slipped it in there, didn't I?
平成感のある、懐かしみの感じの楽曲を
It's a song with a nostalgic, Heisei-era feel...
こちらですね、歌わせていただいたんですけれども
That's what I just sang for you.
このあと、この曲が24時から、あと数時間後か
And in just a few hours, at midnight tonight...
1月30日の24時から配信、リリースされます！
at 12:00 AM on January 30th, it'll be released!
たくさん聴いてください！今年もたくさんオリ曲出していきたいです！
Please listen to it a lot! I want to release many originals this year!
そしてそして！MCが実は最後なのでね
And! This is actually the final talk segment,
この配信のあとにはメンバー限定の配信もあるので、よろしくお願いします！
so there'll be a members-only stream after this. Stay tuned!
よし、よし、よし！グッズ紹介！
Alright, alright! Time for merch announcements!
ここには同期の「ねらぼ」が大集合ということで
The whole 5th Gen 'NeLaBo' crew is here!
ね・ら・ぼ！集まれー！
Ne! La! Bo! Assemble!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい！チャチャチャチャ、初めて呼びました。どうも！
Yes! Cha-cha-cha-cha! First time calling you guys that. Hello!
あれ？初だっけ？
Wait, is this really the first time?
ポルカチャンネル初です！
First time on the Polka Channel!
お誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！
Happy birthday! Thank you!
ここまでが流れでございます。はい。
And that brings us to the present. Yes.
待ってたからね、待ってたよ。
We've been waiting for this!
グッズを紹介させていただきたいと思います！
I'd like to introduce the merchandise!
各々リアクションなど取っていただけると嬉しいです！
I'd love to hear your reactions!
ガヤガヤガヤ！
Chatter chatter chatter!
尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念グッズ2026、ラインナップはこちら！
Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration Merch 2026! Here's the lineup!
ドン！ドン！素晴らしい！
Boom! Boom! Amazing!
今回もラインナップが揃っております！
We have quite the lineup this time too!
あれ？なんかちょっと...盛ってません？
Wait... aren't these a bit... extra?
盛ってませんよ！盛ってません！
I'm not being extra! I'm not!
一つ一つ紹介していきましょう！まずはこちら！
Let's go through them one by one! First up!
ポルカのはじめての抱き枕カバーになっております！
It's Polka's very first body pillow cover!
すごい！ポルカ、ちょっと、パンツ履いてません？
Wow! Polka, wait, are you not wearing pants?
丸出しじゃないですか！本当だ！
You're totally exposed! You're right!
部屋着だよ！部屋着！
It's loungewear! Loungewear!
ねねとかだってこういう部屋着だもん！
Even Nene wears loungewear like this!
人のチャンネルだと思ってやりたい放題しやがって！
Just because it's someone else's channel, you do whatever you want!
シャツで寝たらシワつくぞ！
If you sleep in a shirt, it'll get wrinkled!
写真撮影用かもしれないです！なるほどね！
Maybe it's just for the photo shoot! I see!
表が通常衣装で、裏は彼シャツになってます！
The front is my regular outfit, and the back is the 'boyfriend shirt' look!
彼シャツ！パセリ先生ありがとうございます！
Boyfriend shirt! Thank you, Paseri-sensei!
続きまして、ドン！
Moving on... boom!
歴代衣装のポルカ ランダムラバーストラップです！
It's the Polka Random Rubber Straps featuring past outfits!
のいみね先生に書いていただきました！
These were illustrated by Noimine-sensei!
どの衣装が出るかお楽しみに！リアクション100点満点です！
Look forward to seeing which one you get! Perfect reactions, guys!
続きまして、こちら！
Next up, this!
「どれもこれも宝物 思い出バインダー」！
The 'Everything is a Treasure: Memory Binder'!
チェキ風のブロマイドカードとか入れられたり！
You can use it for things like the instax-style cards!
ホロカも入るサイズになってます！思い出しまってください！
It's also sized for Hololive cards! Store your memories in here!
続きましては、こちら！
Next, we have this!
ポルカのしっぽキーホルダー！一周回って流行ってるからね！
Polka's Tail Keychain! These are coming back into style!
平成レトロみたいな感じで！可愛い！
It's got that Heisei-retro vibe! So cute!
こちらもつけてください！ボイスも出ます！
Please get one of these too! And we have voice packs!
ASMRボイスです！「彼シャツポルカの、ただいまの抱擁」
It's an ASMR voice pack! 'Boyfriend-shirt Polka's Welcome Home Hug'.
タイトルもなんか狙ってるじゃん！てぇてぇ展開！
The title is totally aiming for something! How wholesome!
やめてよ！なんで今日同期呼んじゃったんだろう！
Stop it! Why did I invite my gen-mates today?!
恥ずかしくなってきた！添い寝ASMRというか...
I'm starting to get embarrassed! It's like a sleeping-together ASMR...
抱き枕カバーと関係がある仕様になってます！
It's designed to go along with the body pillow cover!
お待たせしました！フルセット購入特典、こちら！
Sorry to keep you waiting! Here's the full-set purchase bonus!
チェキ風ブロマイドカード！直筆メッセージ入りもあります！
Instax-style cards! Some include handwritten messages!
通常が箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りでございます！
The regular version has a foil-stamped signature and message!
特典ボイスとして、「すやすやポルカの、いちばん近い約束」！
As a bonus voice pack: 'Sleepy Polka's Closest Promise'!
フルセット購入特典
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
Full Set Purchase Bonus
「一緒にね、寝ようね」みたいな感じの
"Let's sleep together," something like that,
なんかちょっと添い寝ボイスになってて、
it's become a bit of a co-sleeping voice,
こっちもASMRになってます。
and this one is also ASMR.
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
恥ずかしいな！みんなとやるのこれ！
This is embarrassing! Doing this with everyone!
なんか、エッチな女になってる。
You've become like a sexy woman.
ちょちょちょちょ... すみません、すみません。
Wait wait wait... I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
いいじゃない。
It's fine, isn't it?
新年もね、皆さん改めてこれからよろしくお願いします。
For the New Year too, thank you all for your support.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for your support!
というわけで、今日はみんなで最後一緒に歌うために呼んできたということで、
Anyway, I called everyone here to sing together at the end today,
準備してきました！
so we've prepared for it!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
おー！
Yeah!
ボタ、ねね、ラミ、いこうぜ！
Botan, Nene, Lamy, let's go!
POLKATIC FINALE
脚本は捨てちゃおっか
Shall we throw away the script?
さあ しかと焼き付けよ！
Now, sear this into your memory!
アドリブの熱いパフォーマンス
A hot, ad-lib performance!
屋根裏を飛び出して
Leaping out of the attic,
壮大なステージに響く特別なストーリー
A special story echoing on a grand stage.
瞼の裏には
Behind your eyelids,
虹が紡ぐ星空のメモリー
Is a memory of a starry sky woven by a rainbow.
等身大の愛を込めて
With life-sized love,
想像を超える世界へ
To a world beyond imagination.
誰も知らないでしょ
No one knows, right?
Are You ready?
どんな未来が見に行こうよ
Let's go see what kind of future awaits!
なんて自由だ！笑っちゃうよね
How free! It makes you want to laugh, doesn't it?
ねえ ホログラムよりも先へ
Hey, beyond even the hologram.
誰だって置いてかないよ
We won't leave anyone behind.
ご覧 歓声が呼んでいる
Look, the cheers are calling!
スナップからパッと照らす
Shining instantly from a snap,
人生のスポットライト
The spotlight of life.
バラ色のプレミショー！
A rose-colored premier show!
ここが特等席よ
This is the best seat in the house.
筋書きどおりより
Rather than following a script,
天気次第のエチュード
An etude depending on the weather.
まるで物語
Just like a story,
捕まえてよ
Catch me!
待って
Wait!
ほら
Look!
予想のできない展開に
In an unpredictable development,
ステージは揺れる
The stage is shaking,
格別のストーリー
A special story.
耳を澄ましたら
If you listen closely,
月が踊る
The moon is dancing,
雨粒のハーモニー
A harmony of raindrops.
浮かぶ ふわふわな空想
A fluffy fantasy floating up,
暴走 底なしの本能
Running wild, bottomless instinct.
すべて知りたいでしょ
You want to know everything, right?
Hey guys! 叫べ 気分は最高？
Hey guys! Shout out! Is your mood the best?
最高！
The best!
もっと叫べ 気分は最高？
Shout more! Is your mood the best?
最高！
The best!
ポルカ終わるか？
Will Polka end?
終わらない！
It won't end!
It's showtime!
繋いだ手 離さないでなんてね
Saying things like "don't let go of our held hands."
どうしたって 重たくなっちゃって困るわ
I'm troubled because it inevitably becomes heavy.
いつの日かエピローグを
Someday, an epilogue...
一緒に綴ろう
Let's write it together.
きっと約束よ
It's a promise, for sure.
Life goes on!
どんな未来が見に行こうよ
Let's go see what kind of future awaits!
なんて自由だ！笑っちゃうよね
How free! It makes you want to laugh, doesn't it?
ねえ ホログラムよりも先へ
Hey, beyond even the hologram.
夢のような花舞台に感情を馳せたら
If I let my emotions run wild on this dream-like flower stage,
スナップからパッと照らす
Shining instantly from a snap,
人生のスポットライト
The spotlight of life.
バラ色のプレミショー！
A rose-colored premier show!
どこまでだって添い遂げたい
I want to stay with you wherever we go.
ここが特等席よ
This is the best seat in the house.
あんたにゃ　もったいない
You don't deserve me
あたいはほんと ナイスボディ ボディ ボディ
I've really got a nice body, body, body
自分で言うくらい
If I do say so myself
タダじゃない じゃない じゃない
I'm not cheap, no, no, no
あけにゃ　冷ませば　うん
If you sober up by dawn, yeah
寂しげにゃ エブリバディ ボディ ボディ
Everybody looks so lonely, body, body
誰にもわからない
Nobody understands
恋愛っていつ火がつくのか
When the flames of love will ignite
ダイナマイト
Dynamite
恋はダイナマイト
Love is dynamite
どんなに不景気だって
No matter how bad the economy is
恋はインフレーション
Love is inflation
こんなに優しくされちゃみだら
Being treated so kindly makes me feel wanton
明るい未来に
To a bright future
就職希望だわ
I want to apply for a job
日本の未来は
Japan's future is...
世界がうらやむ
the envy of the world
恋をしようじゃないか
Let's fall in love
ダンス！ダンス！オーライ！
Dance! Dance! All right!
なんだか物足りない
Something's not quite enough
どこに立って愛してほしいわ
Wherever I stand, I want to be loved
自分で伝えるの
I'll tell you myself
恥ずかしくないわ
I'm not ashamed
いっそ二人がいい
I'd rather it be the two of us
憧れよ エブリバディ ボディ ボディ
I long for it, everybody, body, body
誰しも気づいてない
Nobody has realized
恋愛って夢の落とし穴
Love is a dream's pitfall
ミステリー
Mystery
恋はミステリー
Love is a mystery
そんなの不自然だって
Even if they say it's unnatural
恋のインサイダー
A love insider
それでも情熱にされちゃわわ
Still, if passion takes over, wow
幸せくる日も
The day happiness comes...
キャンセル待ちなんの
is still on the waiting list
あんたの笑顔は
Your smile is...
世界がうらやむ
the envy of the world
夢があるじゃないか
You have a dream, don't you?
ダンス！ダンス！オーライ！
Dance! Dance! All right!
Fuwa fuwa fuwa fuwa
ラブ ラブ ラブ マシーン
Love, love, love machine
ラブ ラブ ラブ ステーション
Love, love, love station
ラブ ラブ ラブ ファクトリー
Love, love, love factory
ラブ ラブ イズ ソー ワンダフル
Love, love is so wonderful
日本の未来は
Japan's future is...
世界がうらやむ
the envy of the world
恋をしようじゃないか
Let's fall in love
ダンス！ダンス！オールオーバーザナイト！
Dance! Dance! All over the night!
モニカ娘も
Monica Musume too
あんたもあたしも
You and I too
みんなお社長さんも
Everyone, even the CEOs
ダンス！ダンス！オーザナイト！
Dance! Dance! Over the night!
ラブ マシーン
Love Machine
今日は主役だ！！
Today you're the star!!